As it turns out, just about anything can
be a computer. And that includes slime
molds, blood, your body. We'll talk
about it. Do you guys remember when some
researchers decided to put fungus in
charge of a robotic body? Yeah. They
gave it UV light and it doesn't like UV
light. So, the random electrical
impulses taught them how to move the
body of the robot and it got better at
it. And yeah, they gave it a little car
for some reason. Same group who decided
to make a Terminator skin out of fungus.
Why did they use a Terminator body?
Because researchers have a sense of
humor, too. People ask all the time. Do
scientists watch sci-fi? Yes. Yes, they
do. They get inspiration from it. Now,
what this research group tried to do was
build a practical computer from slime
molds? Turns out, while yes, they can
technically operate a robotic body, they
can also be used as memoristers.
I'm sure you've seen people put
electrodes onto things like plants or
fungus and have them play music, but
it's just coming from random impulses.
Well, you can go further than that. Like
the little robot bodies, they can
remember what happened to them, even use
it to their advantage. In this case, the
natural electrical impulses that they
have along their networks ends up
creating stronger signals. So, in
essence, they remember and that can be
measured. Not too dissimilar to how our
brains work. Having an impulse is
something that is remembered and becomes
stronger. Our brains on their own are
memoristers. Your own DNA in essence is
a computation system. It stores
information, translates it, and provides
you with a body. But you can also encode
information into DNA. You could turn
your personal fingerprint into a cipher
if you wanted to. DNA storage is
perfectly viable and it would degrade
over time as you got mutations, but so
does all information. It degrades over
time. At least you're powered by food
rather than electricity. Actually, you
kind of are also powered by electricity.
That's why we can interface things like
the tiny human brains that you can grow
in a literal jar if you want to with
computers. And I know you guys are tired
of hearing that phrase, but I have
friends who actually work with brain
organoids and they hear my voice in
their head and I love that. I live to
haunt. I have always been a proponent of
borrowing from nature. When we try to
engineer something that looks like a
natural system, often times we go about
it the hard way. We can plagiarize from
nature or even steal from nature and use
biological systems. But I'm a fan of
things that are inspired by nature. The
idea of using things like tiny human
brains or other natural systems as
computers has led to a lot of questions.
If an AI system can accurately predict
human behavior, are we any better than
them? We may actually just be stochastic
parrots just like AI is. We can see that
as AI terms have entered our lexicon,
our
vocabulary. Yes, AI isms have already
changed us as we have changed them. We
have the benefit of randomness, but
every now and again we do misbehave and
that's not all that different than
artificial intelligent systems. I know
AI is not all that smart, but it is
catching up. One of the major problems
that I've discussed here is AI can't run
a soft fleshy body very well unless you
give them a virtual brain. AI is rapidly
catching up in the ways that it is
smarter than people already, like being
able to do complex linear equations in
seconds. Maybe it's misguided, but I do
want to see human beings create
something that will surpass them. We've
had the planet for a long time. My
question, do you think it'll be fungal,
biological, or something entirely
artificial?